export default {
  id: 'grammar_word_4_1',
  name: '문법책 단어 (4-1 / 200자 / 뜻)',
  data: [
    { question: '起こす', answer: ['おこす', '깨우다'] },
    { question: '考える', answer: ['かんがえる', '생각하다'] },
    { question: '相談', answer: ['そうだん', '상담'] },
    { question: '戻る', answer: ['もどる', '돌아가다'] },
    { question: 'お祝い', answer: ['おいわい', '축하, 축하선물'] },
    { question: '出す', answer: ['だす', '내다'] },
    { question: '趣味', answer: ['しゅみ', '취미'] },
    { question: '何', answer: ['なん', '무엇'] },
    { question: '子犬', answer: ['こいぬ', '강아지'] },
    { question: '生まれる', answer: ['うまれる', '태어나다'] },
    { question: 'お菓子', answer: ['おかし', '과자'] },
    { question: '自転車', answer: ['じてんしゃ', '자전거'] },
    { question: '欲しい', answer: ['ほしい', '갖고 싶다'] },
    { question: 'イタリア語', answer: ['イタリアご', '이탈리아어'] },
    { question: 'スケート', answer: ['', '스케이트'] },
    { question: '眠い', answer: ['ねむい', '졸리다'] },
    { question: 'まだ', answer: ['', '아직'] },
    { question: '貼る', answer: ['はる', '(평면과 평면을) 붙이다'] },
    { question: '帽子', answer: ['ぼうし', '모자'] },
    { question: '被る', answer: ['かぶる', '(모자를) 쓰다'] },
    { question: '橋', answer: ['はし', '다리'] },
    { question: '信号', answer: ['しんごう', '신호등'] },
    { question: '曲がる', answer: ['まがる', '돌다'] },
    { question: '誰', answer: ['だれ', '누구'] },
    { question: '汚い', answer: ['きたない', '더럽다'] },
    { question: '池', answer: ['いけ', '연못'] },
    { question: '落ちる', answer: ['おちる', '떨어지다'] },
    { question: '美しい', answer: ['うつくしい', '아름답다'] },
    { question: '違う', answer: ['ちがう', '다르다'] },
    { question: '無理な', answer: ['むりな', '무리한'] },
    { question: '自分', answer: ['じぶん', '자기, 자신, 스스로'] },
    { question: 'フィリピン', answer: ['', '필리핀'] },
    { question: 'ウィーン', answer: ['', '빈 (오스트리아)'] },
    { question: '公園', answer: ['こうえん', '공원'] },
    { question: 'ソウル', answer: ['', '서울'] },
    { question: '今朝', answer: ['けさ', '오늘 아침'] },
    { question: '引っ越す', answer: ['ひっこす', '이사하다'] },
    { question: '引っ越し', answer: ['ひっこし', '이사'] },
    { question: '再来年', answer: ['さらいねん', '내후년'] },
    { question: '再来週', answer: ['さらいしゅう', '다다음주'] },
    { question: '着く', answer: ['つく', '도착하다'] },
    { question: '会議', answer: ['かいぎ', '회의'] },
    { question: '空港', answer: ['くうこう', '공항'] },
    { question: '座る', answer: ['すわる', '앉다'] },
    { question: '息子', answer: ['むすこ', '아들'] },
    { question: 'パンフレット', answer: ['', '팜플릿'] },
    { question: '渡す', answer: ['わたす', '건네다, 주다'] },
    { question: '夫', answer: ['おっと', '남편'] },
    { question: '似る', answer: ['にる', '닮다'] },
    { question: '乗る', answer: ['のる', '타다'] },
    { question: '乗り換える', answer: ['のりかえる', '갈아타다'] },
    { question: '一日', answer: ['ついたち', '(매 달) 1일'] },
    { question: '週末', answer: ['しゅうまつ', '주말'] },
    { question: 'ディズニーランド', answer: ['', '디즈니랜드'] },
    { question: '食堂', answer: ['しょくどう', '식당'] },
    { question: '集まる', answer: ['あつまる', '모이다'] },
    { question: '病気', answer: ['びょうき', '병'] },
    { question: '入院', answer: ['にゅういん', '입원'] },
    { question: '人形', answer: ['にんぎょう', '인형'] },
    { question: 'ネックレス', answer: ['', '넥클러스, 목걸이'] },
    { question: '掛かる', answer: ['かかる', '걸리다'] },
    { question: '給料', answer: ['きゅうりょう', '월급, 급료'] },
    { question: '海岸', answer: ['かいがん', '해안'] },
    { question: '入る', answer: ['はいる', '들어가다, 들어오다'] },
    { question: 'ぶどう', answer: ['', '포도'] },
    { question: '牛乳', answer: ['ぎゅうにゅう', '우유'] },
    { question: '不注意', answer: ['ふちゅうい', '부주의'] },
    { question: '健康', answer: ['けんこう', '건강'] },
    { question: '～上', answer: ['～じょう', '~상 (건강상, 절차상, 미관상 등)'] },
    { question: '理由', answer: ['りゆう', '이유'] },
    { question: '止める', answer: ['やめる', '그만두다'] },
    { question: '煩い', answer: ['うるさい', '시끄럽다'] },
    { question: '出口', answer: ['でぐち', '출구'] },
    { question: '意地悪な', answer: ['いじわるな', '심술궂은'] },
    { question: '大変な', answer: ['だいへんな', '힘든'] },
    { question: '深い', answer: ['ふかい', '깊다'] },
    { question: '危ない', answer: ['あぶない', '위험하다'] },
    { question: '何も', answer: ['なにも', '아무것도'] },
    { question: '答える', answer: ['こたえる', '대답하다'] },
    { question: '苦い', answer: ['にがい', '(맛이) 쓰다'] },
    { question: '浅い', answer: ['あさい', '얕다'] },
    { question: 'シンポジウム', answer: ['', '심포지움 (집단 토론 회의)'] },
    { question: '行う', answer: ['おこなう', '하다, 행하다 (격식 차린 표현, 공식적)'] },
    { question: '名古屋', answer: ['なごや', '나고야'] },
    { question: '出発', answer: ['しゅっぱつ', '출발'] },
    { question: '祖父', answer: ['そふ', '할아버지'] },
    { question: '生きる', answer: ['いきる', '살다'] },
    { question: '泊まる', answer: ['とまる', '묵다, 숙박하다'] },
    { question: '世界', answer: ['せかい', '세계'] },
    { question: '開く', answer: ['あく', '열리다'] },
    { question: '声', answer: ['こえ', '목소리, 소리'] },
    { question: '鳴く', answer: ['なく', '(동물이) 울다'] },
    { question: '生活', answer: ['せいかつ', '생활'] },
    { question: '寂しい', answer: ['さびしい', '외롭다, 쓸쓸하다'] },
    { question: '本当', answer: ['ほんとう', '정말, 사실'] },
    { question: '珍しい', answer: ['めずらしい', '희귀하다'] },
    { question: '始まる', answer: ['はじまる', '시작되다'] },
    { question: '二日', answer: ['ふつか', '2일'] },
    { question: '寄る', answer: ['よる', '들르다'] },
    { question: 'フォーク', answer: ['', '포크'] },
    { question: '箸', answer: ['はし', '젓가락'] },
    { question: '使う', answer: ['つかう', '사용하다'] },
    { question: 'お土産', answer: ['おみやげ', '선물'] },
    { question: '驚く', answer: ['おどろく', '놀라다'] },
    { question: '昼休み', answer: ['ひるやすみ', '점심(휴식)시간'] },
    { question: '次', answer: ['つぎ', '다음'] },
    { question: 'ずいぶん', answer: ['', '꽤'] },
    { question: '相談', answer: ['そうだん', '상담'] },
    { question: '苦手な', answer: ['にがてな', '서투른, 잘 못하는'] },
    { question: '正しい', answer: ['ただしい', '옳다, 바르다'] },
    { question: '急行', answer: ['きゅうこう', '급행'] },
    { question: '頑張る', answer: ['がんばる', '힘내다, 열심히 하다'] },
    { question: '嬉しい', answer: ['うれしい', '기쁘다'] },
    { question: '困る', answer: ['こまる', '곤란하다, 난처하다'] },
    { question: '間に合う', answer: ['まにあう', '시간에 맞추다'] },
    { question: 'お願い', answer: ['おねがい', '부탁'] },
    { question: 'リュック', answer: ['', '배낭'] },
    { question: '酸っぱい', answer: ['すっぱい', '시다'] },
    { question: '固い', answer: ['かたい', '(일반적으로) 딱딱하다, 단단하다 (↔ 緩い)'] },
    { question: '硬い', answer: ['かたい', '(사물의 상태나 사람의 태도가) 단단하다, (문장 등이) 딱딱하다 (↔ 柔らかい)'] },
    { question: '堅い', answer: ['かたい', '(사람, 사물 성질이) 견고하다 (↔ 脆い)'] },
    { question: '柔らかい', answer: ['やわらかい', '부드럽다'] },
    { question: '騒ぐ', answer: ['さわぐ', '떠들다, 소란피우다'] },
    { question: '予習', answer: ['よしゅう', '예습'] },
    { question: '復習', answer: ['ふくしゅう', '복습'] },
    { question: '連休', answer: ['れんきゅう', '연휴'] },
    { question: '込む', answer: ['こむ', '붐비다, 막히다'] },
    { question: '喫茶店', answer: ['きっさてん', '찻집, 커피숍'] },
    { question: '太る', answer: ['ふとる', '살찌다'] },
    { question: '取る', answer: ['とる', '집다, 취하다'] },
    { question: '年', answer: ['とし', '나이'] },
    { question: '年を取る', answer: ['としをとる', '나이를 먹다'] },
    { question: '洋服', answer: ['ようふく', '옷, 양복'] },
    { question: '似合う', answer: ['にあう', '어울리다'] },
    { question: '不幸な', answer: ['ふこうな', '불행한'] },
    { question: '携帯電話', answer: ['けいたいでんわ', '휴대전화'] },
    { question: 'しょうゆ', answer: ['', '간장'] },
    { question: '漫画', answer: ['まんが', '만화'] },
    { question: '箱', answer: ['はこ', '상자'] },
    { question: '具合', answer: ['ぐあい', '상태'] },
    { question: 'スーツ', answer: ['', '슈츠, 양복'] },
    { question: '背広', answer: ['せびろ', '양복'] },
    { question: '横浜', answer: ['よこはま', '요코하마 (지명)'] },
    { question: '～行き', answer: ['～ゆき', '~행'] },
    { question: '手袋', answer: ['てぶくろ', '장갑'] },
    { question: '費用', answer: ['ひよう', '비용'] },
    { question: '閉まる', answer: ['しまる', '닫히다'] },
    { question: '決まる', answer: ['きまる', '결정되다, 정해지다'] },
    { question: '冷蔵庫', answer: ['れいぞうこ', '냉장고'] },
    { question: '直す', answer: ['なおす', '고치다'] },
    { question: '洗濯物', answer: ['せんたくもの', '세탁물, 빨랫감'] },
    { question: '乾く', answer: ['かわく', '마르다, 건조해지다'] },
    { question: '焼ける', answer: ['やける', '구워지다'] },
    { question: '探す', answer: ['さがす', '찾다'] },
    { question: '釣る', answer: ['つる', '낚다'] },
    { question: '味噌', answer: ['みそ', '된장'] },
    { question: '足す', answer: ['たす', '추가하다'] },
    { question: '増える', answer: ['ふえる', '증가되다'] },
    { question: '沸く', answer: ['わく', '끓다'] },
    { question: '慣れる', answer: ['なれる', '익숙해지다'] },
    { question: '冷房', answer: ['れいぼう', '냉방'] },
    { question: '役に立つ', answer: ['やくにたつ', '도움이 되다'] },
    { question: '触る', answer: ['さわる', '만지다, 손대다'] },
    { question: '聞こえる', answer: ['きこえる', '들리다'] },
    { question: '通る', answer: ['とおる', '지나다, 통과하다'] },
    { question: '思い出す', answer: ['おもいだす', '생각나다, 상기하다'] },
    { question: '変わる', answer: ['かわる', '바뀌다, 변하다'] },
    { question: '足りる', answer: ['たりる', '족하다'] },
    { question: '機械', answer: ['きかい', '기계'] },
    { question: '可笑しい', answer: ['おかしい', '이상하다, 웃기다'] },
    { question: '通う', answer: ['かよう', '다니다'] },
    { question: '株', answer: ['かぶ', '주식'] },
    { question: '旅行', answer: ['りょこう', '여행'] },
    { question: '八百屋', answer: ['やおや', '야채가게'] },
    { question: '厳しい', answer: ['きびしい', '심하다, 엄격하다'] },
    { question: '勤める', answer: ['つとめる', '근무하다'] },
    { question: '育てる', answer: ['そだてる', '기르다, 키우다'] },
    { question: '打つ', answer: ['うつ', '때리다, 치다'] },
    { question: '野菜', answer: ['やさい', '야채'] },
    { question: '神様', answer: ['かみさま', '하느님'] },
    { question: '祈る', answer: ['いのる', '기도하다, 빌다'] },
    { question: '飾る', answer: ['かざる', '장식하다, 꾸미다'] },
    { question: '晴れ', answer: ['はれ', '맑음'] },
    { question: '亡くなる', answer: ['なくなる', '세상을 떠나다, 별세하다'] },
    { question: '光る', answer: ['ひかる', '빛나다'] },
    { question: '直る', answer: ['なおる', '(고장난 것이) 고쳐지다, 수리되다'] },
    { question: '止む', answer: ['やむ', '그치다'] },
    { question: '壁', answer: ['かべ', '벽'] },
    { question: 'ペンキ', answer: ['', '페인트'] },
    { question: '塗る', answer: ['ぬる', '칠하다'] },
    { question: '踊る', answer: ['おどる', '춤추다'] },
    { question: '謝る', answer: ['あやまる', '사과하다'] },
    { question: '払う', answer: ['はらう', '지불하다'] },
    { question: '結果', answer: ['けっか', '결과'] },
    { question: '沸かす', answer: ['わかす', '끓이다'] },
    { question: '痛み', answer: ['いたみ', '통증'] },
    { question: '叶う', answer: ['かなう', '이루어지다'] },
    { question: 'クオリティ', answer: ['', '퀄리티'] },
    { question: '悲しい', answer: ['かなしい', '슬프다'] },
    { question: '恥ずかしい', answer: ['はずかしい', '창피하다, 민망하다, 부끄럽다'] }
  ]
}
